Ronald Travis Bare

Mount Juliet, TN 37122

Phone: 615-881-0624 | Email: travisbare@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ronaldtbare | **Github**: https://github.com/ronaldtbare | **Portfolio**: https://ronaldtbare.github.io/Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer at Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp with a background in Education and lifelong dedication to learning. M. Ed Instructional Effectiveness, B.S. Industrial Technology. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Over twenty years of experience in teaching computer/art/technical courses.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Git and Github, Node.js, Express, React, some Python **Applications:** VS Code, MS Office, Linux, MySQL, MongoDB, Autodesk Creative Suite, Blender

PROJECTS

Google Book Search | Github: https://github.com/ronadltbare/booksearch | **Deployment**: https://travisbarebooksearch.herokuapp.com

Summary: MERN stack project to search for books using CRUD operations on a database.

Responsibilities: Entire application.

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node

ServUs Nashville | **Github:** https://github.com/ronadltbare/project2 | **Deployment**: https://radiant-tor-14793.herokuapp.com

Summary: Volunteer community board where users can post volunteer jobs for like-minded people who are interested in volunteering.

Responsibilities: Database creation and connectivity.

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Jquery, MySQL, Node, Heroku

 $\textbf{Psychic Game} \mid \textbf{Github:} \text{ https://github.com/ronadltbare/Psychic-Game} \mid \textbf{Deployment:}$

https://ronaldtbare.github.io/Psychic-Game

Summary: Simple Javascript based game with interesting logic.

Responsibilities: Entire Applicatoin

Tech: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript,

EXPERIENCE

Instructor 2010 – 2018

Art Institute | Nashville, TN

- · writing lesson plans, administrative tasks
- · Media Arts and Animation Department
- courses: History of Animation, Hard Surface and Organic Modeling, CG Lighting and Texturing, Advance Lighting, 3D Modeling, Character and Technical Modeling, Perspective Drawing, 3D Character Animation, 3D Character Rigging, Motion Graphics and VFX.
- In-service presentations

Teacher 2010 - 2012

Metro Nashville Public Schools | Nashville, TN

- · Developed the CAD/Design program.
- · writing lesson plans, administrative tasks
- subjects taught: Computer-Aided Design, Advanced Drafting, and Design

Instructor 1997 – 2010

ITT Technical Institute || Nashville, TN

- · implementing and maintaining classroom management procedures
- subjects: 3D Modeling and Animation, Rapid Visualization, Basic Design Theory, Digital Information Management, Architecture I & II, Engineering Graphics I & II, Descriptive Geometry, Civil Drafting and GIS
- In-service presentations

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt Coding Bootcamp | Nashville, TN

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS. Certification.

Master of Education – Instructional Effectiveness

Trevecca Universtiy | Nashville, TN

Bachelor of Science – Industrial Technology

Berea College | Berea, KY

18 Graduate Hours – Multimedia and Animation Academy Art University || San Francisco, CA